A Finding Aid to the E. P. (Edgar Preston) and Constance Richardson papers, 1814-1996, bulk 1921-1996, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Collector files, 1921-1981; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 24-25
  - Hatch, John Davis, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Ingersoll, Sturgis, 1968-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Izard, circa 1954-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Jefferson, Thomas, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Johnson, John G., 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Latro, Joseph Capece, circa 1954-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Lea, Dr. Isaac, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Manigault, Charles, circa 1954-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Middleton, Henry, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Morris, Gouverneur, circa 1954-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Newbold, W.R., circa 1954-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Phales (Philadelphia), 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Smith, Mr. & Mrs. Joseph Allen - Saint Memin, 1965-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Smith, William Longhton, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - de Somerlous, Marquis de, 1951-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Starr, F. Morris, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Watson, John Fanning, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Wilstach, W. P., 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 24)
- Bibliographic Index Cards, circa 1930-1982; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 25
  Three index card file boxes of 3x5 index cards created by Richardson contain titles and authors, and occasionally notations, of books and articles on history and art. Folder titles are from the original file boxes.
  Arranged in original order.
  - American History, circa 1930-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Carton 25)
  - Pennsylvania, Philadelphia General, circa 1930-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Carton 26)
  - American Artists, circa 1930-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Carton 27)
- Professional and Committee files, 1895, 1930-1981; bulk 1930-1981; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 2.2 Linear feet Boxes 26-28
  Professional and committee files document Richardson's professional and consulting work for the Art Quarterly, Detroit Institute of Arts, National Collection of Fine Arts, the National Portrait Gallery, the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, the John D. Rockefeller III collection, Winterthur Museum, and the White House. Also included are folders containing of his professional opinions on paintings and sculpture (in the form of correspondence), and a folder on the Historical Society of Pennsylvania. Files include meeting minutes, reports, correspondence, booklets, clippings, and photographs.
  Arranged alphabetically by organization or subject.
  - Art Quarterly, Correspondence, 1966-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts, Correspondence, 1942-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 2-3)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts, Correspondence, 1942-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts, Correspondence, 1950-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 6-8)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts, Correspondence, Resignation, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts, "Hand Book of Paintings," Compiled by James E. Scripps, 1895; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts, Notes and Insurance, circa 1930-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Historical Society of Pennsylvania, Correspondence, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - National Collection of Fine Arts, Correspondence, Minutes, Reports, 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - National Collection of Fine Arts, Correspondence, Minutes, Reports, 1965-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - National Collection of Fine Arts, Correspondence, Minutes, Reports, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - National Collection of Fine Arts, Correspondence, Minutes, Reports, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - National Portrait Gallery, Acquisition Materials, 1968-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - National Portrait Gallery, Booklets, Correspondence, Minutes, 1969-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - National Portrait Gallery, Commission, 1964-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - National Portrait Gallery, Committee on Research and Publication, 1967-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - National Portrait Gallery, John Walker's Affair, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - National Portrait Gallery, Nagel, Charles, 1966-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - National Portrait Gallery, Next Meeting, 1973-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - National Portrait Gallery, Policy for Collections, 1967-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - National Portrait Gallery, Smithsonian Institution Correspondence, Minutes, Reports, 1966-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Opinions on Internal Revenue Service, Mr. Ruhe, Art Objects, 1966-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Opinions on Paintings, 1966-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Opinions on Paintings and Sculpture, Given, 1962-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Annual Report and Meeting Minutes, 1970-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Catalog and Acquisitions, 1976-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Centennial Fund, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1966-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Gribbel, John II, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, History, 1972-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Kaufmann, Arthur C., 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Merriam, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Next Meeting, 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Peale Club, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Print Collection, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Quarterly, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Randolph, Evan, 1967-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Resignation, 1969-1970, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Rockefeller, John D. III, General, 1976, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Rockefeller, John D. III, "Man of the Arts" Chapter by John E. Harr, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Rockefeller, John D. III, Not Used in Final Group, 1970-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Rockefeller, John D. III, Paintings List, circa 1970-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Rockefeller, John D. III, San Francisco Catalog, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Winterthur Museum, American Paintings, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 24-25)
  - Winterthur Museum, Art Cataloging and Information, 1976-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 26-28)
  - Winterthur Museum, du Pont, Henry F, 1966-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Winterthur Museum, Friends of Winterthur, 1966-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Winterthur Museum, General, 1979-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Winterthur Museum, Paintings, 1976-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Winterthur Museum, Resignation, 1945-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - White House Consulting, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - White House Festival of the Arts, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - White House Fine Arts Committee, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - White House Wyeth Dinner, 1970-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 6)
- Constance C. Richardson papers, 1929-1996; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 28-29, 30
  Constance C. Richardson's papers include business and professional correspondence with various institutions including the Carnegie Institute, De Young Museum, and San Francisco Museum of the Fine Arts, and most extensively with the Macbeth Gallery. In addition, there is a smaller amount of personal correspondence, photographs of a drawing of Constance by Alison Farmer, a folder of financial records, biographies, clippings, photographs, transparencies, and slides of her artworks, exhibition catalogs, two illustrated notebooks on her work (with titles, dates, dimensions, sites, names of purchasers and galleries where shown), and miscellaneous notes. Also included is Constance's artist palette.
  - Archives of American Art - Photographs of Intial Survey of E.P. Richardson Papers, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Artist Supply Materials, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Artists Equity Association News Letters, 1947-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Artworks - Photographs, 1928-1969, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 10-13)
  - Artworks - Transparencies, circa 1960-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 14-18)
  - Artworks - Slides, 1959-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Biographies, circa 1944-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Catalogs, Invitations, circa 1950-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Clippings about CCR, 1944, 1961-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Clippings - Newspaper Articles, 1941-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - "Constance" by Alison Farmer Jan 1966 - Photographs of, Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Aram, Siegfried F., 1943-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Business, Professional, 1936-1991, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 3-14)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1952-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition and Catalog Materials, circa 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Financial Records, 1935-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Notebooks, 1929-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Notes, circa 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Palette, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 20)
    Oversized material housed in Box 30, Folder 2
  - Talk - Draft Typescript, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Writings, Poems, Various Authors, 1965, 1982, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Oversize palette from Box 29, Folder 20, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 30, Folder 2)
    Oversize material from Box 29, Folder 20